[Music]
today i went on a quest to find a
secluded meadow in the mountains
i brought my camera and backpack and for
a moment i stopped breathed and admired
the view
i then began to search for the magic
i pursued a butterfly for about 20
minutes before it evaded me
obviously i spent time looking for
fairies
i fell a few times on slippery rocks got
quite sweaty and was tempted to be
grumpy all the way back due to an old
knee injury acting up
but when i got home and looked over the
footage i remembered how the effort to
get there was so well worth it
i've reiterated the sentiment a couple
times but these videos are the product
of the part of me that loves art and
storytelling
and there's a reason that the visuals
seem more reminiscent of a fairy tale
perhaps
than stark reality
i seek out unusual angles and ways of
portraying beauty because i think
there's value in looking at the world
that way
to imbue what i do with my imagination
and romantic sensibilities
visualizing myself as a character in my
own book of fairy tales
only i can't read ahead to find out how
it ends and i suppose that's the best
part
[Music]
for example since i've started making
videos i've embraced being a total
weirdo on my nature walks i sometimes
wear my favorite dresses walk barefoot
when i can and don't worry what passing
hikers may think if they find me
crawling along the ground to get a good
photograph of a butterfly
instead of admiring the flowers from
above as i walk past now i stop and
wonder what it would look like from a
different angle
i like to imagine myself as a little
wood mouse and get down on my knees and
look through the grass
it's amazing what you notice
[Music]
in the same way that we go to watch a
movie in a theater see an art exhibit
watch a play or read a fantasy book i
firmly believe there's a lot of benefit
of enjoying your imagination and taking
a little break from the more mundane and
worrisome aspects of life in order to
breathe deeply and exist
differently for a while
possibly to entertain that romanticism
on a daily basis
seeing each day is a new chapter to a
wondrous tale
personally i believe our view of reality
is far too narrow
for example many people don't see the
dream world as part of their reality and
yet when we go to sleep and have dreams
we are experiencing it and it's a very
real part of our lives
i remember when i was a child and firmly
believed unicorns existed
and i would readily argue with anyone
who told me otherwise
but as an adult i've realized that
whether or not they ever physically
existed isn't really important
because they exist in this world through
our art ideas and stories
they're a part of our reality
similarly perhaps healthy forms of
escapism isn't escaping at all but
simply broadening the spectrum of the
life experience
perhaps it's simply a question of
embracing what you love and not where
but how you want to live and beginning
to do it right now
as long as we're not avoiding the
challenges of life and making progress
in our story and development i find that
fantasy and romanticizing aspects of
life have enormous power to help us
unlock our potential
[Music]
i think that the greatest gift i gain
from looking at life this way is that it
relies on embracing a more positive and
hopeful outlook
after working as a teacher i know that
our little people are looking to us as
an example of how to handle a future
that at times can feel very uncertain
by showing them that we need to seek out
the beauty of imagination and nature and
be the artist of our own lives we can
make lasting change and our life story
becomes a legacy
of not only what we did but the people
with which we connected and helped
we need to understand our reality to
experience the tragedies and heartache
to know them fully and ask ourselves
what we can do to help
and then we have to know how to dream to
imagine a better world to seek out the
good in order to build peace
to nurture our own dreams when others
doubt themselves
maybe i'm an idealist but
i wouldn't want to be anything else
[Music]
do
about three years ago i was living in an
apartment right by a highway that was so
close it experienced a mini earthquake
every time a truck went by
it was infested with rats it was
disgusting and definitely not up to code
but it was the only place i could find
on short notice
i lived with a couple that were
constantly fighting and calling the
police
one night i was woken up by a
firefighter because a drunk driver had
backed into our gas pipe and the house
was flooded with fumes
it was definitely not an easy time but i
deeply embraced my love of stories and
exercised my imagination more than ever
during that year and it really helped me
stay positive about the future while
finding little ways to improve the
present i read so many books during that
time and re-watched my favorite movies
again and again
and every weekend i would take the bus
to a little park and spend time writing
very bad poetry
i tried to see my story as something
that was ever evolving and that has
turned into a theme i applied in my day
that is what i've always sought to do in
these videos to present reality not
always as it is but how it could be
sometimes of possibilities and magic
like most of us i spend the majority of
my time working and submerged in that
more mundane reality
but when it comes to these videos i can
create something that helps me
appreciate it more to seek to capture
the special moment so i can remember it
better
[Music]
[Applause]
do
[Music]
lastly i wanted to say a big thank you
to everyone who has connected with me in
regards to this channel
it is so beautiful to meet so many
kindred spirits from all over the world
to receive your outreach of words and
art and letters and to find people who
value the act of dreaming together
well i cannot reply to all of you myself
i want to tell you that i truly
appreciate it and i'm sending you my
love
you